<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Tim Raphael</title><link>https://tardoe.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Tim Raphael</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tardoe.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Buy vs Build Monitoring</title><link>https://tardoe.github.io/posts/buy-vs-build-monitoring/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tardoe.github.io/posts/buy-vs-build-monitoring/</guid><description>Monitoring a network of any reasonable size, to the extent where failures can be accurately detected, is a non-trivial task. To some extent, the monitoring component could be more complex than the functionality and operation of the network itself once you consider external impacting factors.
Monitoring can be one of those things that can be made as complex as you want it to be and can take into account as many factors as you want.</description></item><item><title>Enriching Metrics with Prometheus</title><link>https://tardoe.github.io/posts/enriching-metrics-with-prometheus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tardoe.github.io/posts/enriching-metrics-with-prometheus/</guid><description>Metrics without context can be hard to explore and even harder to understand, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re in the depths of troubleshooting a difficult issue. Prometheus provides us with a useful pattern that allows you to match metadata with scraped metrics and attach new labels.
Why? Useful details can be added to metrics by pulling from a database, source of truth platform such as Netbox or other inventory systems. Say you&amp;rsquo;re scraping node-exporters that are exposing data from a data centre of hypervisors, it might be useful to add additional metadata about each server&amp;rsquo;s geography or data centre location.</description></item><item><title>Common Tasks in LVM</title><link>https://tardoe.github.io/posts/common-tasks-in-lvm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tardoe.github.io/posts/common-tasks-in-lvm/</guid><description>Because dealing with LVM is a fairly uncommon task for me, I tend to find myself googling these same procedures over and over again. They are documented here for my own benefit and anyone else that is looking for a clean, simple process document.
I pretty much use Ubuntu exclusively, so these examples are all in Jammy 22.04 LTS.
Reminder about LVM Structure Physical Volume (PV) &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Volume Group (VG) &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Logical Volume (LV)</description></item></channel></rss>